James Gross NLRB Files /4057
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD (OLD) 1934-1935 (JULY)
  - Sub-Series A. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD RECORDS
    - Sub-Series 3. REPORTS AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS 6/34-8/35
      - Reports (Box 1, Folder 58)
        Undated; Memo on Industrial Labor Relations Board; memo on the Coercion amendment; House Amendments to S.1958; bibliography of leading materials upon Sec.7a; statement of the managers on the part of the House; memo on the Wagner-Connery Bill; the Wagner Act (?); press release of Francis Biddle's comments on the report of the Special Committee on "The Government and Labor" of the Twentieth Century Fund, Inc.(290); statement before the Senate Finance Committee; the Federal Trade Commission; preliminary report on Boards' handling of Sec.7a cases; Executive Order regulating the further allocation and obligation of funds of the National Labor Relations Board, and prohibiting the further obligation of such funds prior to approval of estimates and expenditures by director of The Bureau of Budget; report to the NLRB on an Inquiry into Industrial Relations Boards; memo concerning the Compliance Division of the N.R.A.; list of regional personnel and salaries; reaction to the Wagner Bill; criticism of the panel system.
    - Sub-Series 4. CLIPPINGS AND REPRINTS 1934-35
      - Clippings, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        3/34-8/34
      - Clippings, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        9/34-12/34
      - Clippings, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        1/35-8/35
      - Reprints, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Reprints, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Sub-Series 5. CASE FILES 12/34-6/35
      - Case files, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        Report submitted by Francis Biddle, Harry Millis and Edwin S. Smith summarizing and affirming the Board's decision of 12/3/34 in the San Francisco Call-Bulletin and Dean S. Jennings case (case no.195); final report on litigation involving Sec.7a - status as of date of Schechter decision.
- Series III. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD 7/35-11/47
  - Sub-Series A. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD RECORDS
    - Sub-Series 1. MINUTES 9/9/35-11/17/47
      - Minutes, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        9/9/35-12/27/35; Members include: Francis Biddle, Charles Fahy, Estelle Frankfurter, Herber Blankenhorn, George S. Wheeler, Benedict Wolf, Dirks, J. Warren Madden, Edwin S. Smith and John Carmody. Summary minutes include discussion of the following topics: administrative reorganization, the function and eventual appointment of industrial economists (specifically David Saposs), Executive Board orders and instruction to regional boards, and appointments and resignations among regional board members. Also discussed are reports from lawyers in the field, cases involving discrimination suits against union members, and a conference between the NLRB and Aldel and Roundtree of the Public Works Administration (P.W.A.) on unfair labor practices in P.W.A. projects.
      - Minutes, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        1/2/36-12/22/36; Summary minutes includes a discussion of the following subjects: the revision of Rules and Regulations, the influence of the Guffy decision, the Federal Register's refusal to print "cease and desist" orders, a memo concerning Nathan Shefferman, the Boards' decision to discontinue use of the Mackay Radio Corp. because it violated the NIRA, and a 28 page narrative account of the meeting of the Departmental and Field Staffs of the NLRB. (This account gives an historical, ideological and legal interpretation of the Wagner Act, as well as discussion of legal procedure.)
      - Minutes, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        1/21/37-12/16/37; Summary minutes of the Executive Board and Lodge 301 (NLRB) include discussion of the A.F.ofL.- C.I.O. conflict (Marathon Electric Co., Warsaw, WI, and John Morrell & Co., Ottumwa, Iowa), and a resolution concerning racial prejudice. Nearly 100 pages of narrative minutes concerning the Regional Directors Conference. Subjects discussed include procedures, settlements, and A.F.ofL.- C.I.O. cases.
      - Minutes, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        1/13/38-12/15/38; Summary minutes of the Executive Board and Lodge 301 (NLRB) include a discussion of police brutality toward black citizens in Washington, D.C., Colonial River Lines barring blacks, and authorized enforcement at Cowell Portland Cement Co. (Cowell, CA). Also included are references to the following subjects: the La Follette Sub-Committee, the O'Connell Peace Act, Washington Friends of Spanish Democracy, the American League for Peace and Democracy, the National Anti-War Congress, and the Women's Trade Union League (W.T.U.L.).
      - Minutes, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        1/19/39-11/28/39; Members include: Condon, Karro, Kaufman, Killens, Koplow, Burnstein, Eden, Landy, Prince, Freeling, J. Warren Madden, Edwin S. Smith, William Leiserson, Charles Fahy, Emerson, Myers, Elliott, Patterson, Nathan Witt, Toland, Kay, Robinson, and Nydorf. Minutes of the Executive Board and Lodge 301 (NLRB) include discussion of the following subjects: amendments to Rules and Regulations, preparation for the House Investigation, the Smith Committee's improper treatment of Lodge 301 (NLRB) members, methods of handling decisions in representation cases, an account of Leiserson calling for Witt's and Krivonos' resignations. Also included are over 30 pages of narrative minutes on a conference on the supervision of regional boards, and discussion of an authorization and appeals units. References made to the following subjects: the Marian Anderson Committee, the Washington Youth Council, Max Steiner, the Wagner Health Bill, and the 5-day week.
      - Minutes, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        10/11/40-10/23/40; Minutes of the Executive Board include discussion of the use of informal files, and letters from the civil Services Commission regarding Marie Prince and Sara Steinberg Gordon.
      - Minutes, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        10/12/44-20/26/44; Narrative minutes include over 30 pages of discussion by the legal staff on the following subjects: majority-rule, jurisdiction, and "R" and "C" cases.
      - Minutes, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        11/22/46-12/5/46; Members include: Gerhard Van Arkel, Consedine, and Lazarus. Summary minutes include discussion of the following issues: strikes against Board certifications or collective bargaining orders, unfair labor practices, employer petitions, closed shop provisions, mediation and arbitration, prohibition of strikes and lockouts in public utilities, and the transfer of prosecuting functions to the Dept. of Labor.
      - Minutes, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        11/17/47; Narrative minutes of the NLRB Union and Robert N. Denham (General Counsel, NLRB) include a discussion of the posting of job vacancies.
      - Minutes (Box 2, Folder 16)
        Undated; Minutes are in summary and decision only form. Includes discussion of the Pennsylvania Greyhound Co. case.
    - Sub-Series 2. CORRESPONDENCE 7/19/35-3/19/70
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 17)
        7/19/35-10/15/35; Letter from William Green (President, American Federation of Labor - A.F.ofL.) to the President suggesting individuals to serve on the NLRB; from Edwin S. Smith to Herber Blankenhorn concerning appointees to the NLRB, and discussing Biddle's reason for leaving; from Gerhard Van Arkle to Calvert Magruder on revisions to Sec. I of Article IV; from Edwin S. Smith to Magruder and Benedict Wolf with regard to mediation and settlement activities under the the "New Act"; from J. Warren Madden (Chairman, NLRB) to Edwin S. Smith on the industrial economist; from L.A. Knapp to Magruder recommending changes in the 8/29/35 draft of "Instructions to Staff Members"; from John A. Lapp (U.S. Dept. of Interior, Petroleum Labor Policy Board) suggesting that the Petroleum Board be made an agency of the NLRB; personal letter from Lloyd Garrison to J. Warren Madden congratulating him on his chairmanship, and discussing Bob Watts (head of the litigation staff); Harold L. Ickes' (Administrator Petroleum Industry) and Madden's discussion of the status of the Petroleum Labor Policy Board; letter to (unattached) Rules and Regulations from the Board to Stanley Mathewson (Director, Regional Labor Board, Region 9) informing him that Louis Jaffe will act as a legal assistant; from Francis Biddle to Madden about the Philadelphia Regional Board; from Robert Watts to the Board concerning the Jones and Laughlin Steel Co, and the Pennsylvania Greyhound Lines cases; from G.L. Patterson (Regional Attorney, Detroit) to the Board providing background on prospective cases including: the Fruehauf Trailer Co. (flagrant discrimination), the Chrysler Motor Corp. (failure to bargain collectively, & recognition), and the Packard Motor Car Co. (discrimination); from G.L. Patterson to the Board regarding information on the Duplex Printing Co.'s unfair labor practices; incomplete collection of legal memos from Charles Fahy (General Counsel, NLRB) to All Regional Attorneys, including a lenghty (12pp) discussion of "The Bargaining Unit" by G.L. Patterson, and suggested changes in Rules and Regulations made by William Green; from Fahy to Madden on the criteria for choosing Regional Attorneys; from Madden to Dr. Jacob Billikopf discussing the status of the Philadelphia Regional Board, and suggesting its former members act as an Advisory Board to the Regional Director; from Ross to Madden recommeding a response to an inquiry from Ralph M. Easley about violations of Sec.9a; Madden's letter to Easley; from G. L. Patterson (Regional Attorney, Detroit) to the Board requesting authority to issue a complaint in the Fruehauf Trailer Co. case (5pp); from Herber Blankenhorn to Madden, John Carmody, and Edwin S. Smith concerning the A.F.of L. convention, and the attitude of the NLRB; from Elinore Herrick to the staff forbidding charges to be shown to employers; from Stanley S. Surrey to Charles Fahy discussing the "Entent to which the Board Must Go in Showing the Effect Upon Interstate Commerce in a Particular Case and Manner of Proof" (10pp); from Nathan Witt (Assistant General Counsel) to Fahy containing draft of complaint of unfair labor practices against the Sands Manufacturing Co.; from C.A. Wood (Chicago Regional Labor Board, Region 13) to Charles Fahy suggesting the Bendix Product Corp. case serve as a test case, and discussing the question of A.F.of L. representation.
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 18)
        10/16/35-12/31/35; Letter from J. Warren Madden to the Honorable Compton II White (House of Representatives) requesting funds for Regional Boards; reply from Madden to Clinton S. Golden (Director, Region 6), attached is Golden's letter of 10/10/35 and a memo (4pp) suggesting an arrangement between Regional Directors and Federal and State Conciliation agencies be established; from Benedict Wolf to Elinore Herrick on procedure involving interstate commerce cases; from Herber Blankenhorn to Madden, Edwin S. Smith and John Carmody regarding the A.F.of L. Convention, including mention of under-cover agencies investigation and the 1936 presidential election; a lenghty (9pp) letter from Charles H. Logan to the NLRB in regard to the Gulf Longshoremen, (includes a detailed, dramatic, narrative account of the New Orleans situation describing factional leaders, organizations, and issues); significant correspondence concerning the Fruehauf Trailer Co. case, specifically the issue of interstate commerce; correspondence relating to the Greyhound Lines case; correspondence regarding the selection of trial examiners; from Estelle Frankfurter to Benedict Wolf on consent elections; from Charles Fahy to all regional attorneys on allegations of interstate commerce; from L.W. Berman (regional director) to Wolf about the International Filter Co., contains criticism of the Old Board, and William Greens' list of "Don'ts;" from Blankenhorn to J. Warren Madden, John Carmody and Edwin S. Smith on the status of employees discharged for union activity; from Wolf to the Director of region 2 (New York), giving the director and attorney authority to issue complaints without first reporting to the National Board; from John A. Lapp to Madden offering the Petroleum Board's personnel and files; from Philip Levy to Madden on the application of the NLRA in the District of Columbia; discussion of the selection of employee representation; from A.L. Wirin to Charles Fahy previewing economic data with regard to interstate commerce and the Friedman-Harry Marks Clothing Co.; from Nathan Witt to Fahy concerning the Sands Manufacturing Co., and the position of the A.F.of L. in this case; from Daniel M. Lyons to Fahy on the jurisdiction of the Bituminous Coal Labor Board, and a discussion of the application of the Wagner Act with relation to the Constitution and the Guffey decision; from Blankenhorn to Edwin S. Smith about the Brown Shoe Co. case, contains a reference to "union-busting," and the undercover agency of A.A. Ahner; from Wolf to Major William J. Mack ordering him to act as trial examiner in the Timkin Silent Automatic Co.; from Fahy to the Board on the legal staff personnel; J. Warren Madden, Frances Perkins and A.L. Wirin discussion of use of the Bureau of Labor Statistics files; from Robert H. Cowdrill to Wolf concerning the Guide Lamp Corp. case and an attached "Report of Investigation and Recommendation RE Complaints;" from Herber Blankenhorn to Fahy on the interstate character of labor relation policy; from Wolf to Saul F. Danaceau appointing him trial examiner in the Sands Manufacturing Co. case; from Wirin to Dr. Henry Moskowitz in regard to the clothing industry, and suggesting a change in emphasis in his affidavit; from Wolf to Regional Directors ordering an informal weekly report be submitted to the National Board; from Blankenhorn to the Board regarding his meeting with William Green, includes comments on "big fellows in steel"; from Blankenhorn to Robert M. LaFollette (United States Senate) requesting advice about setting up a Senatorial Committee to investigate espionage and the disruption of unions; from Paul H. Kilian (President, O'Neal Industrial Service Co., Division of O'Neal Secret Service, Inc.) to the President of Mastercraft Corp. soliciting his company's services; from Wirin to Louis Waldman with regard to the Friedman-Harry Marks Clothing Co. case, particularly discussing Weinberg (a lawyer who waived his right to cross-examine a witness, and did not present testimony); a recommendation from Joseph Rosenfarb to amend Sec.8c; from Edwin S. Smith to J. Warren Madden presenting a plan whereby each Board member supervises one third of the regional offices; from Blankenhorn to the Board about the field work on the undercover agencies investigation; report from Charles Hope (Director, Region 19), including a record of the workers' concensus of opinion on the Wagner Bill.
      - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 19)
        1/4/36-3/31/36; Excerpt from the monthly report by Edwin S. Smith calling for a new text on labor economics; from Edwin S. Smith to Marvin McIntyre requesting a meeting with the President to discuss emergency funding from Congress; from Edwin S. Smith to Madden on materials for Supreme Court Briefs, and suggesting arguments have a "social responsibility" orientation; from Charles N. Feidelson to the Board with regard to the Aluminum Company of America (ALCOA) and the labor leader Wetmore; a report from (N.?.) Schleifer to Nathan Witt on the Pioneer Pearl Button Co. recommending a complaint be filed charging unfair labor practices; from Madden to William G. McAdoo (U.S.Senate) dissuading him from taking Wirin before the Senate for endorsement of, or association with, or defense of Communists (7pp); from Charles Hope to Edwin S. Smith confirming permission to go to Alaska and investigate the Alaska Juneau Gold Mining Co.; from Lloyd Garrison to Madden alerting him to the possibility of a dispute between an industrial union and a trade union; from Blankenhorn to Madden, Carmody and Edwin S. Smith on the status of the Lewis Movement; from Wolf to the Staff on the organization of formal and informal files; from the President to the Secretary of Labor informing her that NLRB statements and reports will be forwarded; enthusiastic letter from Blankenhorn to Senator Edward P. Costigan recommending a Senatorial Committee to investigate undercover agencies; from Louis E. Jaffee to the Board about the Columbia Enameling and Stamping Co.; from Thomas I. Emerson to Madden on the Ellenbogen Textile Bill; from A.N. Somers to Charles Fahy on " the effect of courts' doubt as to constitutionality of the National Labor Relations Act on an application for a preliminary injunction;" from Elinore Herrick to the International Longshoremen's Association concerning the Banana Handlers Association; from G.L. Patterson to Robert Watts about the Chrysler Corp. case, and the General Motors Truck Corp. case (both representation cases); from Charles Fahy to David Moscovits concerning the Mackay Radio & Telegraph Co.; correspondence relating to the Jones and Laughlin case and the issue of manufacturing as interstate commerce; correspondence between Watts and Clifford O'Brien welcoming him to the litigation staff, and assigning him to the Carlisle Lumber Co. case, also included is a discussion of the constitutionality of the Wagner Act; from Charles Fahy to all attorneys concerning the preparation of defenses in injunction suits (27pp); from Blankenhorn to Madden on the Federal Laboratories Inquiry; annual report 1936 from Blankenhorn to Madden about SR266: senate investigation of interference with labor rights, etc.; from Wolf to Leon M. Daspres appointing him trial examiner in the Pioneer Pearl Button Co. case and reminding him that the Board "assumes its own constitutionality;" from Charles Hope to Edwin S. Smith, Charles Fahy, Robert Watts and Benedict Wolf pertaining to the Carlisle Lumber Co. case, relating an episode in which Judge Charles Paul and Bruener disappeared minutes before they were to resume court; from Frank H. Bowen to the Board praising G.L. Patterson's work in the Chrysler and General Motors cases; from Fahy to all regional directors regarding the filing of affidavits refutting injunction; from George S.Wheeler to J. Warren Madden on transit privileges; from Herber Blankenhorn to Robert LaFollette about the investigation of undercover agencies and preliminary hearings; from Nathan Witt to Fahy concerning office routine; correspondence between the President, Stephen Early, and Edwin S. Smith about the President's speech which is to be prepared by the Board; outline of a suggested new approach to state legislation for mediation and arbitration in labor disputes (7pp); a plan for a bill providing for mediation and arbitration; from Fahy to Thomas Emerson making him a liaison between the administrative and litigation divisions; from Fahy to the Board explaining the priority in which cases will be handled; from Madden to Dr. H.F. Hinrichs (Acting Commissioner of Labor) requesting statistical assistance from the Dept. of Labor; from Jerome N. Frank (Chairman, Securities and Exchange Commission) to Madden discussing the circumstances under which registrants are required to make disclosure of labor disputes to which they are parties; correspondence concerning the appropriation of $119,435; from Wolf to all regional directors concerning strike data as proof of interstate commerce; from Madden to Congressman Robert Ramspeck refutting the notion that the Board is suspending action after decisions are won (with respect to the Atlanta Woolen Mills, and Standard Hat Co. cases); possible address on the NLRB prepared by Edwin S. Smith for the President; urgent letter from Blankenhorn to LaFollette telling him to set up a Federal investigation on undercover agencies; from Fahy to Madden on borderline cases, contains references to the Pressed Metals of America, Inc. case, and the Gordon Bakery case; from Blankenhorn to Edwin S. Smith stating that the War Dept. has withdrawn from publication its field manual on domestic disturbances; from Blankenhorn to Madden, Carmody and Edwin S. Smith in regard to Dan Tobin's (President, Teamsters Union) attack on Lewis' industrial union movement; from Madden to Senator William G. McAdoo defending Wirin in regard to Senator Walsh's endorsement; from Blankenhorn to Madden, Carmody and Smith setting the date for the LaFollette Committee hearings.
      - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 20)
        4/1/36-6/29/36; Memos to the NLRB and regional attorneys on whether investigation under Sec.9c should be authorized; correspondence relating to the Columbia Enameling & Stamping Co. case; Elinore Herrick's and the Board's discussion of the International Mercantile Marine Co. case R-24, focusing on employer repression, the Black significant correspondence concerning the Guffey decision, includes a letter from Charlton Ogburn (Attorney) to Madden with an attached memo on the effect of the Guffey Act Decision on the National Labor Relations Act; letter from Sumner H. Slichter (Professor of Business Economics, Harvard University) to Madden questioning the obligation of an employer who has bargained in good faith toward employees on strike, and Nathan Witt's reply; from Madden to Harold L. Ickes (Sec. of Interior) questioning the Dept. of Interior's judgement in awarding a contract to the Jones and Laughlin Steel Co.; from Charles Hope to Edwin S. Smith about the Auto Mechanics cases in Portland and Seattle, includes references to the loggers lockout in the Columbia River Basin area, and the Tillamook area; correspondence relating to the American Potash and Chemical Corp. case includes a letter from Bertram Edises (Region 15) to Charles Fahy; from Herber Blankenhorn to J.P Harris instructing him to "organize" steel, includes example of telegrams to be sent to John Brophy and John L. Lewis; from Witt to the Board on review of records by the Board; from Blankenhorn to Madden, Carmody and Edwin S. Smith on tension between the A.F.of L. and the C.I.O.; reply from Charles West (Acting Sec. of Interior) to Madden stating he has withdrawn the award from Jones and Laughlin Steel Co.; several memos to Benedict Wolf from various regional officers in regard to the Regional Directors and Attorneys Conference, and subjects for discussion; dramatic memo from Herber Blankenhorn to Madden, Carmody and Edwin S. Smith on the curtailment of Board hearings, especially in manufacture; from Charles Fahy to the Board regarding the Associated Press election; from Edwin S. Smith to Claude A. Swanson (Sec. of the Navy) questioning the Navy's judgement in awarding a contract to the Wheeling Steel Corp. which has failed to comply with a Board decision; from Estelle Frankfurter to all regional directors and attorneys, "a summary of remarks on the obtaining of material available from government agencies."Diamond plan and the use of the secret ballot; 17 memos and 6 letters from Herber Blankenhorn to Robert LaFollette, J. Warren Madden, John Carmody and Edwin S. Smith on the LaFollette Committee hearings and Resolution 266; from Madden to George H. Dern (Secretary of War) questioning the War Dept.'s judgement in awarding United Aircraft Manufacturing Corp. a contract after the Board found the corporation guilty of unfair labor practices; from Nathan Witt to Madden presenting a memo from the legal staff to the Board on working conditions, included are signatures and comments of the legal staff; from Fahy to the Board, "a synopsis of our present and prospective situation in the circuit court of appeals;" detailed, narrative memo from E.J. Eagen to Charles Fahy on the Alaska Juneau Gold Mining Co. case XIX-C-14, reporting the particular circumstances relating to the case (i.e. geography, Russian and American workers), including a discussion of the communist faction of union members, and public officials response to it; correspondence concerning the LaFollette Committee, largely from Herber Blankenhorn to Robert LaFollette, or the Executive Board; from Robert H. Cowdrill to Benedict Wolf on collective bargainig and the rights of minority groups; reply from Harry H. Woodring (Acting Sec. of War) to Madden contending that the War Dept. lacks the authority to withhold contracts from United Aircraft Manufacturing Corp.; from Towne Nylander (Director, Region 21) to the Board in regard to the Oregon Worsted case; correspondence relating to the Pennsylvania Greyhound Lines Inc., case C-1 including particular attention to Lester R. Moberly; correspondence concerning the Jones and Laughlin case, including an annotated memo from George S. Wheeler to the Board critizing the Jones and Laughlin brief; from the President to Harry L. Hopkins asking him to check the figures that appeared in the New York Sun, "Who Keeps Them Out of Work, Industry or Roosevelt;" reply from the Comptroller General of the United States to J. Warren Madden on expert witnesses; correspondence between Herber Blankenhorn and John L. Lewis, subjects discussed include the Porthsmouth Strike, the steel industry and Clinton Golden; from Dorothy Altachuler to Blankenhorn on Wagner's speech to the National Women's Trade Union League of America; from Charles Fahy to the Board recommemding Professor Willis W. Ritter for the position of Principle Attorney, Litigation Division; from Elinore Herrick to Benedict Wolf about Crucible Steel Co. case, no. 11-R-4; from Edwin S. Smith to Charles Hope in regard to the automoblie dealers' situation, and the issues of interstate commerce and jurisdiction; from Charles Fahy to Harold Cranefield on the International Filter Co.